Guide to the Cynthia Farah Haines papers related to Literature and Landscape: Writers of the Southwest M2107
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Cynthia Farah Haines papers related to Literature and Landscape: Writers of the Southwest
circa 1985-1988
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Haines, Cynthia Farah, 1949-
M2107
9 Linear Feet 20 boxes (8 msbs, 6 fbs, 3 card boxes with negatives and audiocassettes, 7 books, 1 DVD, 1 CD)
Research material and photographs used in the production of Cynthia Farah Haines' 1988 book Literature and Landscape: Writers of the Southwest.
Scope and Contents
Cynthia Farah Haines (born 1949) is a photographer, film critic, and scholar who received her BA at Stanford, and began her critical career writing for the Stanford University Daily. Her book "Literature & Landscape: Writers of the Southwest, " published in 1988, features photos and biographical text about 50 Southwestern authors. The collection contains notes, correspondence, drafts, photos, negatives, audiocassettes, and other material.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Cynthia Farah Haines, 2015.
Authors, American -- 20th century; Southwestern States -- In literature.; Haines, Cynthia Farah, 1949-
- Series 1. Writers: Literature and Landscape (A-Z & Misc.)
  - Edward Abbey, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rudolfo Anay, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Byrd Baylor, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Elroy Bode, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Richard Bradford, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ernest J. Burrows, 9/15/1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Angelico Chavez, 8/21/1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Denise Chavez, 4/12/1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Peggy Pond Church, 8/21/1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - William Eastlake, 7/21/1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Max Evans, 6/16/1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Floyd Fierman, 2/1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bernard Fontana, 7/1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Gene Frumklin, 6/16/1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Joy Harjo, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tony Hillerman (file A), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tony Hillerman (file B), 11/17/1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rolando Hinojosa-Smith, 11/17/1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Paul Horgan, 10/21/1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dorothy B. Hughes, 11/26/1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Arturo Islas, 4/12/1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Elmer Kelton, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - David Lavender, 11/17/1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tom Lea, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Harold Littlebird, 3/21/1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mark Medoff, 10/1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Leon Metz, 2/1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - N. Scott Momaay, 11/17/1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pat Mora, 12/13/1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gary Paul Nabhan, 11/17/1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John Nichols, 8/23/1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanley Noyes, 3/22/1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lawrence Clark Powell, 4/18/1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jim Sagel, 3/22/1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Richard Shaefer, 7/15/1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Jack Schaefer, 8/22/1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marc Simmons, 8/22/1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - John Sinclair, 5/1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Somoza, 5/20/1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - C.L. Sonnichsen, 4/18/1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stan Steiner, 8/24/1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth Tallent, 8/16/1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Luci Tapahonso, 3/21/1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Sabine R. Ulibarri, 9/12/1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Frank Water, 4/18/1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Marta Weigle, 9/14/1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Jeanne Willams, 9/13/1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Keith Wilson, 5/20/1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Norman Zollinger, 6/15/1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ann Zwinger, 11/17/1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Southwest writers, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chicana writers, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - BRLA Southwest Book Award, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Author of The Pass/El Paso Writers Hall of Fame, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lit and Land/Clark Kimball, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series 2. Writers, Non-Literature and Landscape
  - Jimmy Santiago Baca (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reyner Banham, 11/1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Chuck Bowden (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Conrey Bryson, 1/10/1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jose Antonio Burciaga, 8/6/1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Gary Cartwright, 8/3/1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Jose Cisneros, 2/1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sandra Cisneros, 2/19/1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Juan Contreras, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - James Day, 8/8/1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lalo Delgado, 10/1/1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rick DeMarinis, 2/1/1989 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - T.R. Fehrenbach, 2/1/1989 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gordon Frost, 3/1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Francis Fugate, 9/11/1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Aarell Gibson (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Dagoberto Gilb (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Francis Gillmor (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Erlinda Gonzales-Berry (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Don Graham (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Nancy Herndon (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Clark Kimball (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Larry King (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - W. David Laird (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Josefina Lopez (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Tom Lyon (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Frank and Judy Mangan (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - E .A. Mares (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Demetria Martinez (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Oscar J. Martinez (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Patricia Preciado Martin (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Leo Marx (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - James McCarthy (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Howard McCord (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - William McGaw (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Larry McMurtry (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Larry McMurty (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miguel Mendez (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Tom Miller (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Carlos Norton (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dwight and Carol Myers (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Antonia Nelson (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Marguerite Noble (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Naomi Shihab Nye (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Louis Owens (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Leroy Quintana (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Gregory Ramos (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Diana Rebolledo (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - John Rechy (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Jack Rittenhouse (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Leo Romero (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Orlando Romero (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Benjamin Saenz (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Robert Skimin (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Toby Smith (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Arthur Sze (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Pat Ellis Taylor (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - W.H. Timmons (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Stephen Trimble (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Stuart Udall (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Leslie Ullman (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Abraham Verghese (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Victor Villasenor (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dale Walker (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Kathleen West (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Joseph Wilder (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Series 3. Photo Sales/Exhibits: Literature and Landscapes
  - Cynthia Farah Haines: HI Books Signing, 10/8/1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - SW Writers Traveling Photo Exhibit, 2/13/89 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Old Southwest/New Southwest Conference Tuscon, 11/14/1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Open Spaces, City Places: Tucson, November 19-21, 1987, 11/21/1987 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Book Dealers, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photos Sold/Anthologies, 6/1/1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cynthia Farah Haines CV (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Series 4. Literature and Landscape Audiocassettes & DVDs (Box 10)
- Series 5. Photographs & Negatives
  - Literature and Landscape: Negatives of 50 Authors (Box 11)
  - Literature and Landscape: Signed and Archival Photos (Box 12)
  - Literature and Landscape: Extra Archival Prints (Box 14)
  - Southwest/ Writer Negatives (Box 17)
  - Archival Prints, Authors Not in Literature and Landscape (some signed) (Box 18)
- Series 6. Books
  - Literature and Landscape books (Box 19)
  - Literature and Landscape: Manuscript signed first edition (Box 13)
  - Books (Box 20)
- Series 7. Literature and Landscape: Original Questionnaire (Box 15)
- Series 8. Texas Western Press publicity (Box 16)